嗚汪！你再也不能這樣叫了
Bow wow! You can't bark like that anymore.
因為…這個星球上的一切都被燒盡
Because...everything on this planet is burnt,
融化 壓碎了…
melted, crushed...
人類已經死亡 腐爛
Humans are dead, rotten,
狗狗們在他們的身上啃啊啃
and the doggie is nom, nom, nom, noming on them like it's a feast.
話說 食物可是很重要的！
I mean, isn't food important, after all?
因為“人如其食”所以要小心啊
Yes, you must be very careful because you are what you eat.
吃了不該吃的東西的話
So when someone eats something they shouldn't eat,
會怎樣呢？
what happens then?
會怎樣呢?!
What happens then?!
他們的身體會變得與之前不同
Well, that person becomes something they are not,
這就是說…
and that means...
是的 這意味著…
Yes, that means...
他們來了
Oh, here there are.
他們好可愛喔
They're so cute, huh?
他們在找什麼？
Are they searching for something?
他們好像嗅到了什麼
Oh, and it appears they smell something.
這邊的也很可愛！
Ooh, these guys are adorable, too!
拉近鏡頭 攝影師！
Zoom in, Mr. Cameraman!
看不出他們的表情
I can't read the expressions on their faces,
所以不知道他們心情如何
so I'm not sure how they feel.
但這正是他們的可愛之處！
But that's what's so gosh-darn cute about them!
啊！好棒！
Oh! Fantastic!
之前還那樣的溫文爾雅
Unlike their delightfully civilized entrance,
現在變得好粗暴
that was quite savage!
真棒！謝謝你 世界！
(意語)Bravissimo! (日語)Arigato,world!
今天又被吞食掉了
I am devoured once again today,
被完全徹底地撕開了
completely and neatly split open.
然後我終於想起
And then I finally remember.
我從不曾擁有什麼
I had nothing forever and ever.
還有我們在地球上
And we are on planet Earth...
還有我們在地球上…
And we are on planet Earth and...
我在說什麼？
What was I saying?
女仆咖啡廳   雲雀
停！
No!
“拌拌勻咖哩飯”是要在客人的面前拌勻的
Mixy-Mixy Curry Rice needs to be mixed in front of the customer!
所以才叫“拌拌勻”的
It's Mixy-Mixy for a reason,
所以不要在上桌前就拌勻 明白了嗎？！
so don't mix it before you take it to the table, all right?!
酷美 親愛的 早安
Oh, hello, Hidomi, dear. Good morning.
酷美 小心那個女人 騎著 Ve——
Hidomi, beware of the woman on the Vesp--
下一個 帕菲“苦中帶甜不求回報的愛”
Next, Bittersweet Unrequited Love Parfait.
路上小心！
Have a nice day, dear!
糟透了
A nightmare.
別忘了那個女人 騎著 Ve——
Don't forget, the woman on the Vesp--
F  L  C  L
Freebie  Honey
本字幕由 SweetSub 製作　僅做交流學習之用途
翻校：ピロピラ ピロコ　其它：tastySugar
嘿 喲！你們的老師 晴子
Hey, yo! I'm your teacher, Miss Haruko!
你們所在的世界
The world you live in
正在不負責任地溢出
is now overflowing irresponsibly.
不管你看向哪裡
No matter which direction you look,
到處都有人用自私的妄想
you'll see the world is full of those who defile others
汙染其他人和周圍的環境
and their surroundings with selfish delusions.
我真心地相信
And I truly believe that this is solely
這全都是這世上大人們的錯
the fault of the adults of this world,
與此同時 很不幸地
and when I say that, I unfortunately,
我也是他們中的一員
include myself among them.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我的想法和以前不同了
I cannot think like I used to.
我不能繼續下去
I can no longer continue.
噗噼噼
Pupipi.
即使我努力去為這個星球考慮
Even if I try to think what's best for this planet,
我只會想到以前不曾注意的鼴鼠
I think about the mole that I haven't noticed before,
或是它身上的毛髮
or the hair that grows out of it.
沒辦法 我總是想到這些東西
I can't help but think about these things.
世界 宇宙
World. Universe.
實話說 我不在乎
To be honest, I don't care.
因為這不是我的錯
Because it's actually not my fault.
噗噗噗
Puppuppu.
噗噼噗
Puppippu.
乖 好孩子們
There, there. You're good kids. Good talk.
說了那麼多 餓死了 剩下的時間大家自習
Well, I'm hungry, so use the rest of class for self-study.
差點忘了說 好消息
Before I forget, I have good news.
年鑑終於做好了
The yearbook has finally been completed.
來看看吧
So check it out!
年鑑？
Yearbook?
看 這是運動會的！
Oh, hey, that was from Sports Day!
我記得很清楚！
I totally remember that!
那次真是厲害
Yeah, it was epic.
球技大會
晴子老師為了讓對方出局
Miss Haruko's wicked pitch
故意投出的壞球 真夠惡意
when she gets them to pop it for an easy out.
最後一輪晴子老師滿壘下的逆轉封殺時
Miss Haruko's last round full base comeback line
勝利!!
擊中投手的那個平飛球！
drive to the pitcher! -Whoa!
太厲害了！
-Yeah! -Legendary.
美好的記憶
Good times.
放學後召喚UFO！！
放學後向 UFO 發出信號
We sent a signal to a UFO after school,
邀請靈能力者來文化祭
and we invited that psychic to our Cultural Festival.
還有 在掰彎勺子大賽中
Plus, during the spoon bending competition,
晴子老師掰彎了對手的手指獲得了勝利
Miss Haruko bent her opponent's fingers and won!
在慶祝派對上我們用學校樓頂搞了一場篝火
Hmm. And we used the school building to make a bonfire at the after party.
♪ 燒啊 燒啊 燒啊 燒啊... ♪
♪ Burn, burn, burn, burn, burn, burn, burn, burn... ♪
真是美好的記憶啊
These sure are some great memories.
我們是最好的班級
Man, we had the best class ever.
我們真的很幸運
Yeah. We sure were lucky, weren't we?
♪ 灰燼飛舞眼前 ♪
♪ See the embers as they fly by ♪
♪ 火光照亮夜空
♪ Burn into the night sky
雲雀弄…嘿？
Hibaji...Hey?
幫我轉交個東西吧？
Can you deliver this for me?
給井出親 他今天沒來學校
For Ide-chi. He was absent.
為什麼找我？
Why do you want me to do it?
我也不知道 為什麼呢？
I don't know. Why, indeed?
因為你們關係不錯？
Because you two are close?
對吧？
Am I right?
-我說錯了嗎？-不曉得
-Well, are you? -I don't know.
嗯？
Hmm?
OK！謝啦！
Okay! Thank you!
媽媽 這公園好無聊
Mommy, this park is boring!
確實有點舊 需要改造了
Well, it is a bit old. It needs to be updated.
掃地機器人！
Neato!
看起來像從外太空來的！
Looks like it's from outerspace!
哇！好酷！
Whoa! Cool!
我還要工作多久？！
How much longer do I need to work?!
嘿 公主小姐
Hey, princess!
你在這個地方做什麼？
Whatever you doing in these parts?
-你是店裡的客人 -你看這樣如何？
-Oh. You're the customer. What do you say?
要不要成為職業人士？
How would you like to become a pro, huh?
你會很厲害的 成為業內翹楚
You'll be great. A real phenomenon.
她才不會想要做職業人士！
She's not gonna wanna be a pro!
請您別纏著她 她不是——
Please leave her alone, sir. She isn't -- Mmm?
-你是個拉丁裔啊？-呃 是的
-You have Latin blood in you, don't ya? -Well, yeah.
那你呢？要不要做個職業人士？
How about you? Wanna be a pro?
你會很厲害的
You would be great.
成為業內翹楚的
A real phenomenon.
抱歉打斷你 先生
Hate to break it to you, sir,
你才不會隨隨便便在大街上找到業界翹楚
but you're not just gonna find a phenomenon off the streets.
我們走
Let's go.
你的拳頭不錯
You have a fine fist.
我跟你說 你應該成為職業人士
I'm telling you, you should become a pro.
所以 到底是職業的什麼？
Yeah, but a pro what?
那麼 我們來想想
Uh, well, let's see.
你是來給井出帶作業的吧？
You're dropping off Ide's worksheet, right?
嗯
Yeah.
像你這樣的女孩子一個人在這裡很不安全
This isn't really a great place for a girl to come by herself.
雲雀弄 你確定想看到井出真正的樣子嗎？
Hibajiri. Are you sure you wanna see the real Ide is like?
這是什麼意思？
What do you mean by that?
好吧 反正你馬上就要看到了
Well, like it or not, you're about to see for yourself.
就在這！
Here you go!
別停下！
Come on, keep it moving!
你們這些弱柴 就這點能耐嗎！
You gotta give me more than that, you weaklings!
是的 長官
Sir, yes, sir!
你們以為桌上的食物是白給你們的嗎？！
Who do you think is responsible for the food on your table?!
不要想偷懶 你們這些雜碎！
Now, put your backs into it, you pieces of shit!
那可不是國中生的身體
That's not the body of a middle-school kid.
那個肌肉線條雕刻完美的身體
That beautiful, sculpted body that is comparable,
完全不輸於我！
yet superior to mine!
快點 動起來！
Hurry up and move it!
接著做事 沒種的小子！
Get back to work, you dickless brat!
是的 長官！
Yes, sir!
他剃著板寸頭 假裝是班上的小丑
He pretends to be the class clown sporting a buzz cut
整天裝傻
and acting all dumb at school,
其實他生活中吃飯都困難
but in reality, he's actually struggling to make ends meet.
但他從不會向我們展現他生活的另一面
But he wouldn't show that side of his life to any of us, though.
是的 長官
Sir, yes, sir!
那邊的 跑起來
You there! Pick up your feet!
一二一
Hut! Hut! Hut!
來看看啊！這價格可優惠了！
Come, check it out! You can't beat these bargains!
井出製造廠
這是高性能的訂製武器
These are high performance custom weapons,
由本天才手工製作
lovingly crafted by this genius, right here.
這是能發射一百個石子的自動式機槍
This one's an automatic machine gun that can fire 100 pebbles!
而且它只能用5毫米直徑的石子
And it only takes pebbles that are exactly 5 millimeters!
功能多樣
It's very versatile.
我知道你在想什麼
Now, I know what you're thinking,
“哪裡有這種尺寸的石子”
"But, sir, I cannot possibly find pebbles that size."
那麼 我可有解決辦法呢
Well then, do I have the item for you?
睜大眼睛看吧!
Feast your eyes!
這是超級奇怪強大的粉碎機
It's the super eccentric almighty pulverization machine,
能在幾秒鐘之內把岩石碾碎成 5 毫米直徑的石子
crushing rocks into 5-millimeter pebbles in more seconds!
你說什麼？不方便攜帶？
What's that, you say? You can't carry all of this?
對於需要幫忙搬運器材的人
Well, for those who need help lugging around their equipment,
我準備了這個！看！
I have this! I present to you,
絕讚的百發石子機槍和超級奇怪強大的粉碎機
the magnificent 100-shot pebble machine gun and super eccentric almighty pebble
專用手推板車！
pulverization machine dolly!
-這不就是個普通的板車 -嗯？
-Looks like a normal dolly to me. -Hmm?
好了 那麼
All right, then.
你們誰想先來試試？
Now, which of you would like to try it first?
這位老哥 要來試試嗎？
You wanna give it a go, tough guy?
やめろ！
Yamero!
他們為什麼不住手？
Why won't they stop?
他們不知道“やめろ”的意思嗎？
Don't they know what"yamero"means?
他用他們的語言說了 但是他們還是不聽
He's speaking their language and they still won't listen.
我好心痛
Just breaks my heart.
你說這是什麼？[嗶]逗我嗎？（日語）
なんだこりゃ～　バ〇？
沒辦法殺人的機槍？別搞笑了
何の道殺せなねぇマシンガンなんで　笑わせんねぇ
這種廢物拿來有什麼用
いなねぇよ　こんなガラクタ
やめろ！不要 别這樣 求你了
Yamero! No, no, no! S-Stop it! Stop it, please!
閉嘴！
黙れ！
還想要再揍你一頓嗎？
もっと殴られたいのか
讓你們失望了 抱歉
Sorry to disappoint.
你們不管怎麼打我 都不會覺得疼
But no matter how many times you punch me, I feel no pain.
我的心已經凍結了
My heart is frozen.
別！別打了！
No! Please! No!
我錯了！別打了！
Sorry! Stop!
我說錯了話了！
I'm sorry for what I said before!
我錯了！
I'm sorry.
真挫
ダサい
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
我去 怎麼了？
Whoa! What the hell?
森？雲雀弄？
Mori? Hibajiri?
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
喂，雲雀弄！醒醒！你怎麼了？！
Hey, Hibajiri?! Wake up! Are you okay?!
為什麼他桃花運那麼好？
Why does he always get all the girls?
交 親愛的！我做了一些燉蔬菜
Koh, dear! I made some stewed veggies for you.
天啊！天啊！
Oh, my goodness! Lordy, lordy!
你又帶了一個女孩回家？！
You brought another girl home again?!
你這個壞小子
Oh, you nasty, nasty little boy.
年輕就是好
Oh, to be so young again.
要知道 想當年我也是個小——
You know, when I was young, I was also quite the little --
快出去！
Get out!
對不起 我沒事的
Sorry. I'm okay.
好吧
Okay.
我忘了問你了 雲雀弄
Oh! I forgot to ask you, Hibajiri.
你是那種喜歡空間的人嗎？
Are, uh, you the type of person who likes space?
我是說 外太空？
Like outerspace?
我們可以去看太空藝術展
We could go to see space art.
畢竟 人與人之間的關係就像星球之間一樣
Ah! After all, relationships are like in the stars...
像 夜空中的星星一樣
or like, stars in the night sky.
不不不不
Mmm. Oh! No, no, no!
我不是說我們倆在交往！
I don't mean we're in a relationship!
我們可以單純去看展覽而已！所以 挑一個…日子
We could just go! So, pick a...date.
不不 不是約會的意思
No, it wouldn't be a date!
-對不起 - 什麼？
I'm sorry. Sorry?
不過謝謝約我
Thanks for asking.
那個...
I guess... Mm-hmm.
如果是井出的話 可以的哦
...if it were with you, Ide, I'd be fine with it.
交往什麼的
To be in a relationship.
Cut！完美！
And cut! Perfect!
真是太完美了 井出親！
That was just perfect, Ide-chi!
棒極了！可以去拿小金人了！
Bravo! Oscar-worthy!
你 你什麼時候起在這裡的？
Wh-- When did you get in here?
-晴子老師?! -大家稍事休息
-Miss Haruko?!  -Everyone, let's take five!
準備拍下一個場景！
Rolling on the next take!
最終場景
The final take.
雲雀… 雲雀…雲雀弄！
Hiba-Hiba-Hibajiri!
啊…溫柔一點！
Aah, please don't be so rough!
別搞了行不行？
Will you cut it out?! Aah!
終於找到你了
I finally found you.
就不能讓我好好上個廁所嗎
Can't you just let me go to the bathroom in peace?
怎麼回事？她是誰？小偷？
W-What's going on? Who is she anyway? A thief?
-不 我認識她 她是… - 你是誰蛤？
-No, I know her. She's... -Who are you?
哈路哈·拉哈路 別裝作不認識我
You can't pretend that you don't know me, Haruhara Haru.
我真後悔認識你
Rue the day I met you.
你儘管後悔 但逃避我無濟於事
You can rue all you want, but you can't escape me.
十是十四是四十四是十四四十是四十
Meter-maid Mary married manly Matthew Marcus.
是因為我知道這都是演戲
'Cause I know all this is an act.
你需要我 你不是一匹孤狼
You need me. You're not a lone wolf.
孤獨者——
Loners are --
哎呀 我輸了
Oh, wait, I lost the game.
你在玩文字接龍嗎？
You're playing a word game?
原來如此
I see how it is.
看來光動嘴是沒用的！
Then we're just going to have to do this by force!
這就是你的方式嗎？
Huh? That's how you wanna do things?
這是我們倆之間的事情
This is a matter between you and me.
所以不要把她牽扯進來
So don't lay a hand on her.
那你就可以用機械手抓著她嗎？
But it's fine for you to use a big robotic hand?
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
雷射！
Laser beam!
逃避我是沒用的！
You can't escape me!
井出！
Ide!
看招！
Take that!
你真是不容易啊！
You've lived a tough life, haven't you?
喂？
Hello?
呃 夫人 我很抱歉 還沒做完
Oh, uh, hi, ma'am. I'm sorry. I'm not finished.
我不是說過交給你了嗎
I told you I'm counting on you
“時尚蛋奶餡餅女僕宅急配” 服務
for my "Maid Delivers Flan Body a la Mode" service!
-所以你應該… -我現在有急事
So, what I need you to do -- I'm in a middle of something!
你要犯和上次同樣的錯誤嗎？！
Are you going to make the same mistake again?!
這樣是不會成功的！
There's no light at the end of this tunnel!
-停手吧！-想的美！
-Just give it up! -No way, Jose!
已經滿壘了
The bases are all loaded!
吃我平飛球！
And it's line drive!
比賽開始！
Play ball!
你不是已經開打了？！
Uh! But haven't you already been playing ball?!
你自己也明白的吧
Come on! You know you're not
這樣做是找不到他的！
going to reach him like this, don't you?!
拉哈路！
Raharu!
你一個人是不行的 沒有我你是找不到他的
You can't do this alone. You can't reach him without me.
-你心知肚明 -用不著尿褲子
You know this. No need to pee-pee in your panties!
你不可能不明白 因為我們倆本是一體！
The reason you know this is because you and I are one!
個 十 百 千 哈哈
1, 10, 100, 1,000! Haha!
我可是被稱為邪惡的火之打者
They call me the Infamous Flaming Slugger!
酷美
Hidomi.
我警告過你不要跟那個女人扯上關係
I warned you not to get involved with that woman.
她只會為了一己之私利用你
She will only use you for her own benefit.
你甚至會因此而死
Worst-case scenario, you could die.
會死？
Could die?
喂 打者 打者 打者!
Hey, batter-batter-batter!
酷美?
Hidomi?
不 酷美！
No, Hidomi!
不可能
No way.
她克服了酶抑制劑？
She overcame the enzyme inhibitor?
抑制？
Inhibition?
咦 那是什麼喵？
Huh? What-What-What is that,nya?
你看起來不錯
You're looking good.
摸摸不可以喔
No touchy.
酷美！
Hidomi!
發生了什麼？
What just happened?
酷美！酷美！
Hidomi! Hidomi!
井出…井出…
Ide...Ide...
別擔心
Don't worry.
幾個小時內你就會恢復了
You'll be recovered in few hours.
你做得不錯 但是
You did a good job. But...
別動！
Hold it right there!
我不管你怎麼想
No matter how you slice and dice it,
她是屬於我的
we know she's mine.
你看起來糟透了
You look terrible.
作業
Worksheet.
你今天沒來學校
'Cause you were absent today.